根据真实事件改编
托马斯勋爵
Lord Thomas.
亨利勋爵
Lord Henry.
安布罗斯勋爵
Lord Ambrose.
罗伯特勋爵
Lord Robert.
沃尔特勋爵
Lord Walter.
你最好别让我失望，查尔斯・格雷
You'd better not let me down, Charles Grey.
- 我在你身上押了20畿尼 - 只有20？如果换成我押，我就押40
- I've got 20 guineas riding on you. - Only 20? I'd double that if I were you.
走，女士们
Come on, ladies.
英格兰 阿尔索普庄园 1774年4月
先生们，绕着跑两圈，听我口令
Gentlemen, twice around the course, on my count.
三，二…
Three, two,
一！
one!
- 跑啊，格雷先生！ - 跑啊，托马斯！
- Come on, Mr. Grey! - Come on, Thomas!
- 跑啊，格雷先生！ - 跑啊，沃尔特勋爵！
- Come on, Mr. Grey! - Run, Lord Walter!
跑啊，格雷先生！
Come on, Mr. Grey!
跑啊，格雷先生，别慢吞吞的
Come on, Mr. Grey. You're tired already.
- 跑啊，格雷先生！ - 再快点！
- Come on, Mr. Grey! - Faster!
大人觉得乔治安娜还漂亮么？
I trust Your Grace still finds Georgiana an attractive girl?
当然了，斯宾塞夫人
Of course, Lady Spencer.
她是上流社会的才女，知节守礼
She's an accomplished lady of quality and devoted to her duties.
能说流利的法语，意大利语和拉丁语
She's fluent in French, Italian, Latin
精通骑术和舞仪，还…
and fully versed in horsemanship and dancing and...
是的，这些我都知道，她是您的骄傲
Yes, I'm aware of all that. She's a credit to you.
我实在想不出有什么
I can't think of anything that would stand in the way
能阻碍一场天作之合
of a singularly happy marriage.
公爵大人并不顾虑这些，斯宾塞夫人
These are not the issues that burden the Duke, Lady Spencer.
大人有繁衍子嗣之责
It is His Grace's duty to produce an heir.
反言之，若能为大人生下承业之子
On the other hand, your daughter may expect
你的女儿必有厚报
a handsome reward when that occurs.
- 谢谢，希顿 - 大人
- Thank you, Heaton. - Your Grace.
大人您尽可放心
Your Grace may rest assured.
本家族女子在这方面从未有失
The women in our family have never forfeited on that account.
那好，既然有此保证…
Well, with that assurance...
就这么办吧
So be it, then.
冲啊，格雷先生！
Come on, Mr. Grey!
很抱歉，女士们，我的马赢了
I do apologize, ladies, but it appears that my horse has won.
查尔斯，再比一次试试
Beat me again, Charles.
- 干得好，格雷先生 - 干得好
- Well done, Mr. Grey. - Well done.
- 我们欠你多少？ - 你欠我40
- So how much do we owe you? - You owe me 40.
- 20，40 - 我的奖赏呢？
- Twenty, 40. - My reward?
你想要什么？
And what do you suggest?
你母亲要见你，乔治安娜小姐
Your mother wishes to see you, Lady Georgiana.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起，妈妈，是不是我们太吵了？
I must apologize, Mama. Were we making too much noise?
不，我亲爱的
Not at all, my darling.
有重要事跟你说，过来
We have more important things to talk of. Come here.
- 我听到一个传言 - 什么传言？
- I have heard a rumor. - Yes?
我很快就要给我的女儿梳妆打扮
That I will soon be addressing my daughter
她很快就要变成德文郡公爵夫人了
as Her Grace, the Duchess of Devonshire.
- 是真的吗，妈妈？ - 是的
- Is it true, Mama? - It is.
德文郡公爵？
The Duke of Devonshire?
我本想将你晚些嫁人，至少等到18岁
I had hoped not to part with you until 18 at the soonest,
但有天赐良缘在前
but, with such a fine match,
再不放你走，我就太自私了
it would be selfish of me not to let you go.
- 他爱我么？ - 当然爱啦
- He loves me? - Yes, of course.
但我只见过他两次
I have only met him twice.
如果是真心相爱
When one truly loves someone,
不需要知根知底也能明白答案
one doesn't have to know them well to be sure, Georgiana.
这就是一见倾心
One feels it right away.
- 我确信，你跟他会幸福的 - 肯定会的，妈妈，我知道
- I do believe you will be happy with him. - I shall, Mama. I know I shall.
片名：公爵夫人
- 来啊！ - 她来了！
- Come on! - She's here!
公爵夫人！公爵夫人！
Your Grace! Your Grace!
- 是她！ - 公爵夫人！
- There she is! - Duchess!
他们想要干嘛？
What do they want?
当然是想来看我，还有我的新婚妻子
To see me and my new wife, of course.
也许会觉得讨厌，但你会很快习惯的
It can be a nuisance, but you'll get used to it.
伦敦 德文郡公爵宅邸
欢迎您，夫人
Welcome, Your Grace.
来啊，小伙子们，雨果，雨果，过来
Come, boys. Come on. Hugo, Hugo. Come.
好，好，好，好
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
很好，对了，往这儿来
It's all right. Yes, yes. This way.
雨果，来，过来
Hugo. Come, boy. Come.
剪刀给我，你们退下
Scissors. You may go.
我这一辈子，一直没弄明白
For the life of me, I could never understand
为什么女人的衣服设计得如此繁复
why women's clothes must be so damn complicated.
这是我们女人用来表达自己的方式
It's just our way of expressing ourselves, I suppose.
你这话什么意思？
Whatever do you mean?
你们男人可以有很多途径表达自己
Well, you have so many ways of expressing yourselves,
而我们只能通过帽子和衣饰来表达
whereas we must make do with our hats and our dresses.
请你上床去，好么？
Would you go to the bed?
一个人必须履行自己的责任
One has to accept one's responsibility.
也许有些事看起来难以承受
Certain obligations come with marriage,
但结了婚就得在某些方面尽义务
no matter how burdensome they may seem.
我懂，但当我和他在一起的时候…
Yes, but when we are together...
我是说我们在一起亲密的时候
But when we are together, intimately, I mean...
我知道，是有点烦人
I know. It can be a bother.
等你给他养了儿子就好了
However, it is only until you have given him a son.
这种事会越来越少，他也不会逼你做了
Then the occasions will become fewer and less determined.
如果他时不时跟我说些什么
I think it might feel different
也许我会感觉好一点
if he would talk to me every once in a while.
不是说他不够亲切，但他从不和我说话
I mean, it's not that he's unkind, but he never talks to me.
我本以为他会像爸爸一样
I thought that he would be like Papa,
在那冰冷的外表下
that under his cool reserve
深藏着一颗多愁善感的心
there'd be a wealth of depth and sentiment,
但他对什么都不感兴趣，除了他的狗
but he isn't interested in anything, apart from his dogs.
对公爵大人别太苛求了，乔
Try not to be too hard on His Grace, G.
他只想好好履行他的职责
He's merely intent on fulfilling his duty.
你说想跟他交流，但又有什么好说的呢？
And as for talking to him, well, whatever is there to talk about?
您说得也没错
No, you're quite right.
我太傻了，还以为凭自己的水平
How foolish of me to think that I should be able to converse
能和我的丈夫交流
with my husband.
耐心，坚忍和顺从，这些是你的武器
Georgiana, equip yourself with patience, fortitude and resignation.
你很快就会有儿子，到那时你就明白了
A boy will come soon enough, and then you'll see.
而我们辉格党(该党反对绝对王权) 认为只有这样才是明智的选择
But we, the Whig Party, simply see this as just, right and sensible.
让独立之号角响彻美利坚 用黎明的丧钟送走奴隶制
Just to bring independence to America. Right to abolish the slave trade.
引自由之风吹拂普罗大众
And sensible to bring freedom to the common man,
在英格兰这片神宠之地
so the blessings of this blessed plot, this England,
所有子民能同享上帝的恩泽光辉
may be more equally enjoyed by all of its inhabitants.
请各位为宴会主人，也是我党的赞助人
I would like to propose a toast to our host and benefactor
公爵大人和美丽的新晋公爵夫人举杯
His Grace the Duke and his beautiful new Duchess.
请各位起身
Please be upstanding.
- 公爵大人和夫人！ - 公爵大人和夫人！
- The Duke and Duchess! - The Duke and Duchess!
很精彩的演说，福克斯先生
Excellent speech, Mr. Fox.
谢谢夸奖，在一群人之前演说总是不难
I thank you. It is always easier to address a congregation of friends,
尤其是当这帮人已经喝醉的时候
particularly when those friends are drunk.
夫人对福克斯先生的演讲有何高见？
And how did the Duchess find Mr. Fox's speech?
我得承认，我还不习惯政治演说
I must confess, I am not yet at ease with political speeches.
特别的遣词方式总让我 摸不透背后的真正含义
Their very form tends to obstruct my view of their actual meaning,
…如果那些言语另有所指
if such there be.
不知演说中哪部分的言语
In which particular section of the speech
让夫人感到“困惑”呢？
did the message elude Your Grace?
总的来说，我非常赞同您的观点
Well, I have great sympathy with your sentiments in general,
但我不明白您说的“我们辉格党人”
but I fail to fully comprehend how far we, the Whig Party, that is,
对自由一词的推行力度到底有多深
are fully committed to the concept of freedom.
- 我们主张扩大选举权范围 - 让所有人参加选举？
- We intend to extend the vote. - To all men?
当然不是，但肯定不止现在这些人 所谓“适度的自由”
Heavens, no. But certainly to more men. Freedom in moderation.
- “适度的自由”？ - 完全正确
- "Freedom in moderation"? - Precisely.
我相信您的苦心孤诣，福克斯先生,
I'm sure you are full of the best intentions, Mr. Fox,
但我要说，如果我有选举权
but I dare say I would not spend my vote,
如此模糊的声明是无法赢得我的选票的
if I had it, of course, on so vague a statement.
一个人要么自由，要么没有自由 自由的定义只有一种
One is either free or one is not. The concept of freedom is an absolute.
不可能有人适度的死亡
After all, one cannot be moderately dead
也不可能有适度的相爱，或者适度的自由
or moderately loved or moderately free.
这永远是一个非正即反的问题
It must always remain a matter of either or.
我想来说几句
I think it appropriate to say a few words.
当…
When...
你去卧室里找找
Could you check the chamber
- 看能不能找到… - 大人
- and see if you can find... - Your Grace.
…其他样式的法国蕾丝？
...different kinds of French lace?
- 有什么问题嘛？ - 没有
- Is anything the matter? - No.
- 您离席了 - 嗯，我已经吃完了
- You just left. - Yes. Well, I had done eating,
那些无聊的讲话我听厌了，烦死了
and those damn speeches bore me to distraction.
看来下次得下禁令，不得发言
I think we have to ban them in the future.
但您是辉格党的主要拥护人啊
But you are the Whigs' main supporter.
没错，我对政治并不反感
Yes. Well, I've no problem with the politics.
只是我无法忍受那些个夸夸其谈
It's just the rhetoric I can't stand.
- 要我陪您去么？ - 我看不用了，这又何必呢？
- Shall I come with you? - No. I mean, why ever should you?
公爵一切都好，只想小憩片刻
The Duke is perfectly well. He simply wanted to rest a while.
先生们，请坐吧
Do sit down, gentlemen.
是不是公爵对演讲的长度颇有微辞啊？
Was it the length of the speech that got the better of the Duke?
当然不是
Certainly not.
他非常喜欢您的演讲
He enjoyed it immensely
他还说希望下次的演讲再长一些就好了
and expressed a hope that next time it would be even longer.
- 夫人请 - 福克斯先生请
- Your Grace. - Mr. Fox.
- 发生了什么事？ - 跟你无关
- What's going on? - Nothing to concern you.
- 我不明白 - 到这边来
- I don't understand. - Come here.
今晚你看上去很漂亮 裙子是你自己设计的？
You look very beautiful tonight. Is this dress your design?
是的，谢谢
Yes, it is. Thank you.
我想你应该不会反对你的丈夫…
Then I think you should allow your husband to appreciate it
对这裙子做进一步的欣赏吧
in a little more detail.
过来
Come here.
- 好，让他们进来 - 有客人？
- Yes, send them in. - Are we having company?
你不觉得这羊肉味道有些奇怪么？
Don't you think this mutton has a funny taste?
- 没有，我觉得很好 - 我觉得有点奇怪
- No. Not really, no. - I think it does.
乔，这是夏洛特，以后她和我们一起住
G, this is Charlotte, and she will be staying with us.
为什么？
Why?
因为她妈妈死了，她也没有别的地方可去
Because her mother is dead, and she has no other place to go.
你是这孩子的父亲？
Have you fathered that child?
她只是…只是一个小姑娘，乔 又不是什么世界末日
It's... It's only a little girl, G. It's hardly the end of the world.
- 你想让我照顾她？ - 这儿有很多空房间
- Are you expecting me to look after her? - We have a house full of vacant rooms.
她不会打扰你的 事实上，她还能帮到你
She needn't bother you. In fact, she may even be of use to you.
可以先学着如何做母亲
You can practice your mothering skills,
直到我们的儿子出世
until our son arrives.
嗯，这羊肉味道肯定不对
No, this doesn't taste like normal mutton.
肯定是有东西串了味，把它拿走好么？
I'm sure there is something the matter with it. Could you take it away?
你觉得这羊肉味道对不对？
Does it taste like normal mutton?
是不是有股味儿啊？给我过来
Does it taste like normal mutton? Come here.
觉得这羊肉味道对不对啊，小刁嘴？
Think it tastes like normal mutton, fussy dog?
谁是小刁嘴啊？
Who's a fussy mutton dog?
你的娃娃有名字么？
Does your doll have a name?
我打赌，她一定喜欢自己的新卧室
I bet you she loves being in her new bedroom.
给她取个名字吧，明天告诉我
You'll have to think of a name and let me know tomorrow.
你能给她想个好名字，对不对夏洛特？
Do you think you'll be able to do that, Charlotte?
我…
I...
- 请你先出去好么？ - 夫人…
- Would you leave us, please? - Your Grace.
你好，夏洛特
Hello, Charlotte.
我叫乔治安娜
My name is Georgiana.
- 晚上好 - 谢谢
- Good evening. - Thank you.
晚上好，女士们
Good evening, ladies.
夫人，您的肚子要是再长一寸 估计就会爆开
An inch more and I do believe Your Grace will explode.
恭维方面，谢里顿总是很在行
Sheridan always knows how to pay a compliment.
还得再等几周
Still a few more weeks to wait.
这么大的肚子，在您身上那是再合适不过了
A huge belly has never been more becoming on anyone.
这方面福克斯是专家，他每次经过镜子
Well, Fox, here, offers an expert opinion seeing, as he does, a giant belly
都能看到一个超大号的肚子
every time he passes a mirror.
如果把您的肚子搁到一个女人的身上 大家都会明白那是怎么回事
If your belly were on a woman, well, we'd all know what to think.
我亲爱的谢里顿，一小时之前 我的肚子就搁在一个女人的身上
My dear Sheridan, an hour ago my belly was on a woman.
你明白是怎么回事了么？
Now what do you think?
以后再想冒犯福克斯先生 在开口之前最好先想清楚
That will teach you to insult Mr. Fox before the gaming has begun.
画得不错
It's very good.
下注时间结束
No more bets, please.
七点
Seven.
夫人又赢了
Her Grace wins again.
再赌一轮吗？
Another wager?
- 您没事吧，夫人？ - 夫人！
- Are you all right, Your Grace? - Your Grace!
是产前阵痛么？我妻子要生产了
Are those labor pains? My wife is in labor.
跟我走
Come along.
我想现在值得举杯庆祝
I think this calls for a toast.
今夜结束前，我也许就有继承人了
I may have an heir before the night is out.
女士们先生们，请允许我介绍： 德文郡六世公爵！
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you the sixth Duke of Devonshire.
德文郡六世公爵！
The sixth Duke of Devonshire!
- 大人 - 我没心情谈话
- Your Grace. - I am in no mood for a conversation.
- 大人 - 我没有心情说话
我祷告时问上帝，我的女儿能否…
But, pray tell me, is my daughter...
你的女儿能否给我生儿子？
Is your daughter at all able to give me a son?
别灰心，大人
Take heart, Your Grace.
只要她身体康健，一定能生
As long as the mother is in good health,
就当这次失误是打草稿好了
consider this mishap a draft,
当成是将得贵子的保证
a promise of what is soon to come.
- 在我们家族… - 我知道，在你们家
- In our family, we... - Yes, I know, in your family,
在你们家
in your family.
大人，告退
Your Grace.
看到光没有？看到没有？
Can you see the light? Can you see it?
- 你好么，亲爱的？ - 还好
- Darling, how are you? - Quite well.
- 她健康么，壮实么？ - 她十分完美
- Is she strong and healthy? - She's perfect.
- 威廉他见你了没有？ - 见了
- Did William receive you? - Yes.
她不是男孩，他很失望吧？
Is he upset that she's not a son?
他只看了她一眼就走了，之后就不见人影
He just glanced at her and then left. I've hardly seen him since.
亲爱的，大人现在也很不好受
It's been a difficult time for His Grace, my dear.
他现在是许多目光的焦点 其中有一些目光绝非善意
Many eyes are upon him and not all of them kind.
她真是太可爱了
She is the loveliest.
- 保姆呢？ - 不用，我自己喂她
- Nurse? - No, I will feed her.
- 你真要喂她么？ - 是的
- Are you sure, darling? - Yes.
即使是女孩，怎么说我也是她的母亲
I am her mother, after all, even if she is only a girl.
来喽
There.
该死的混账！
Hell and damnation!
六年之后
哈瑞尔    小乔    夏洛特
巴斯镇
人在度假的时候
It is always a pleasure
如能聆得一段奇智妙语，总是一桩乐事
when one is on holiday to request a few words of wisdom.
在此我也不多费口舌了
And so without further ado,
下面郑重推出今晚最尊贵的客人
it is a great honor to hand over to our most distinguished guest.
这位贵客在场时，是所有目光的焦点
When she arrives, all eyes are upon her.
不在场时，她依然是一切话题的中心
When absent, she is the subject of universal conversation.
今晚她亮相时所穿的衣着
And what we see her wearing tonight,
到了明天估计就会人手一件了
I look forward to seeing the rest of you wearing tomorrow!
有请引领时尚的女皇，德文郡公爵夫人！
The empress of fashion herself, the Duchess of Devonshire.
我们来巴斯，是为了远离伦敦
We come away to Bath to get away from London,
谁知整个伦敦都跟着来了巴斯
and all of London has come away to Bath.
有人还真开口问过我
Somebody did indeed ask me
我头上戴的是什么鸟的羽毛
what kind of feather it is that I'm wearing.
据说这种珍奇的鸟类，一共只发现了两只
Well, there are only two specimens of this rare bird known to man.
很显然其中一只已在我的头顶上安息了
One of them has clearly ended up on top of my head.
至于那另一只，传闻说已经跑到 托利党(该党支持世袭王权)的办公室去了
And the other, rumor has it, is running for office in the Tory Party.
贝丝・福斯特
Bess Foster.
请原谅
Excuse me.
- 我们还没有彼此介绍过 - 是还没有，我是伊丽莎白・福斯特夫人
- I don't believe we've been introduced. - No, we haven't. Lady Elizabeth Foster.
- 我刚才看见你和我丈夫说话来着 - 是的，他想请我跳舞
- I saw you talking with my husband. - Yes. He wanted to dance.
这可不是他的擅长啊，你拒绝了没有？
That's not usually considered his forte. And you declined?
我现在没兴致找男士作陪
I'm ill at ease with male company for the moment.
谢谢
Thank you.
你为什么来巴斯？
So what brings you to Bath?
我丈夫正在伯恩茅斯与情人寻欢作乐
My husband, Mr. Foster, is enjoying his mistress in Bournemouth
我来这儿解解闷，你呢？
and I wanted some diversion. And you?
公爵想借这儿的温泉治疗痛风
The Duke is taking the waters for his gout.
- 我跟他一起来调养身体 - 真的？
- And I for my health. - Really?
我听说你们来这儿的原因是你无法育子
I heard you were here because you could not conceive a son.
我很抱歉，说这种话太失礼了
I beg your pardon, that was an awful thing to say.
至少这是事实
It was the truth, at least.
请原谅我说傻话，我总是口没遮拦
Trust me to say something silly. I always do, you know.
那你就该答应公爵的请求
Then perhaps you should have accepted the Duke's offer.
你们两个有许多共同点
You have much in common.
我们回去吧，乔治安娜
Home, I think, Georgiana.
- 你住在哪儿？ - 我在镇上租了几间房
- Where are you staying? - I've rented some rooms in town.
- 我们一定还会再见的 - 一定会的
- We must meet again. - We must.
哈瑞儿，过来，到这儿来…摔疼了没有？
Harryo. Come here. Come here. Did that hurt?
- 妈妈 - 我的小天使
- Mama. - My angel.
疼不疼？那儿疼么？让我看看 是不是这只膝盖？
Are you sore? Was that sore? Let me have a look. Was it this knee?
没事，你不会死的
I think you shall live.
好了，看谁先跑到桥那里，听我口令 一，二，三…跑！
Right. First to the bridge on my count. One, two, three. Go.
来啊，哈瑞儿
Come on, Harryo.
- 不，我能赶上她的！ - 我要追上你！
- No, I'm gonna catch her! - I'm gonna catch you!
跌倒爬起，跌倒爬起… 为什么我们就不能恢复得那么快呢？
Up and down. Up and down. Why can't we recover like that?
因为我们在跌倒前，已经走了太长的路
It's too far to fall now.
- 又见面了 - 你好，你的几个女儿真可爱
- Hello again. - Hello. Your girls are lovely.
- 谢谢，你有孩子么？ - 有，三个男孩
- Thank you. Do you have any children? - I do. Three boys.
三个男孩
Three boys.
要能分一个男孩给公爵 估计他什么都肯拿出来
What the Duke wouldn't give for one of them.
- 你的大女儿最不像你 - 是的，我想其中的故事你应该知道
- She is least like you, your eldest. - Yes. I'm sure you know the story.
我丈夫的大女儿是在我们结婚前出世的
My husband's daughter was born before we married.
她的母亲是一名女仆 女仆死后，孩子就交给我们带了
Her mother was a maid. The maid died, and we took the child.
- 对不起，我又说了不该说的 - 没事
- I'm sorry. Have I spoken out of turn? - No.
在伦敦，这是人尽皆知的秘密 她现在已经九岁了
It's the worst-kept secret in London. She's nine years old now.
你爱她么？
And you love her?
当然爱，我对她视如己出
Of course I do. The same as all my children.
来，我给你介绍一下
Come and meet them.
姑娘们，来认识一下妈妈的新朋友 伊丽莎白夫人
Girls. Come and meet my new friend, Lady Elizabeth.
- 夫人，给你 - 谢谢…这是温泉水
- Your Grace. - Thank you. Thermal water.
那股怪味是因为里面有硫黄
It's the sulfur that makes it smell so bad.
- 你真的要把这个喝了？ - 每天两杯，连喝四周
- And you really have to drink it? - Twice a day for four weeks.
难道你相信自己真的不能生男孩？
Do you have any reason to believe you cannot birth a male?
流产前，我一直不信这个
No. Except miscarriages.
两个死胎，都是男孩
Two stillbirths, both sons.
但我也生了两个健康的女孩
But two healthy girls.
每个人都看着你
Everybody is staring at you.
你头颈后面是什么？贝丝？
What's that on your neck? Bess?
法律规定男人不能用棍子抽打妻子
It's not illegal for a man to beat his wife with a stick
除非使用的棍子比他的拇指更细
unless the stick is thicker than his thumb.
福斯特先生？他怎么能这么做！
Mr. Foster? But he can't have done that!
比起他对我做的其他事，这还不算最糟
Well, considering what else he's done to me, that's not the worst.
还有什么更糟的事？
What could possibly be worse?
他带走了我的孩子，还不准我见他们
He's taken my children. He won't let me see them.
- 那你打算怎么办？ - 说实话，我已经无计可施了
- And what do you propose to do? - Really, I'm at my wits' end.
法律站在福斯特先生一边
The law supports Mr. Foster.
那现在你打算去哪儿栖身？
In the meantime, where shall you stay?
继续租房，直到钱花光为止
Continue lodging, till the money runs out.
那这样吧，这方面我还能帮点忙
Well, there, at least, I think I can help.
威廉？明天我们就要离开这儿了
William? We leave tomorrow.
伊丽莎白夫人的娘家在欧洲大陆
And Lady Elizabeth doesn't have to meet her parents on the continent
她也不急着回去
for some time.
- 她几乎没怎么去过伦敦 - 那倒是个遗憾
- She hardly ever visits London at all. - It's a pity, that.
那什么，在伦敦她也没地方可住
You see, she doesn't have anywhere to stay.
这倒是个问题
Problem there.
那好，让她和我们一起住如何？ 先住上一阵再说
Well, why doesn't she stay with us? For a while, at least.
谢谢您
Thank you.
- 太不可思议了 - 那是在爱尔兰的城堡
- This is incredible. - There's the castle in Ireland.
博尔顿修道院，奇斯威克，伯灵顿， …哦，当然还有查茨沃思
Bolton Abbey, Chiswick, Burlington and, why, in Chatsworth, of course.
- 那是当然 - 那一处比别处大得多
- Of course. - Which is much bigger.
但这儿更像家
But this is more like home.
有你在这儿，我说不出有多高兴
I'm so glad you're here.
我还准备了一出很精彩的开场节目
I've arranged a wonderful start to the season.
要是我再试着跟你修好
May all the plagues of marriage be doubled on me
就让婚姻的不幸加倍降临在我的身上！
if ever I try to be friends with you anymore!
要是这样就好了
So much the better.
不，不，夫人。你显然对我毫不关心
No, no, madam. 'Tis evident you care not a pin for me!
我当初娶你的时候准是发疯了
And I, I was a madman to marry you.
我当初嫁你的时候准是糊涂了
And I'm sure I was a fool to marry you,
一个看见女人就追的王老五
an old dangling bachelor
五十岁了还是个光棍
who was single at 50
只因为找不到肯嫁他的人！
only because he never could meet with anyone who could have him!
贝丝, 这位是反对党领袖福克斯先生
Bess, may I introduce Mr. Fox, leader of the Opposition?
- 福克斯先生, 这是伊丽莎白・福斯特夫人 - 福克斯先生
- Mr. Fox, Lady Elizabeth Foster. - Mr. Fox.
- 我的门生，查尔斯・格雷 - 格雷先生
- My protege, Charles Grey. - Mr. Grey.
- 格雷先生 - 夫人
- Mr. Grey. - Your Grace.
他是我们年轻的新星
He's our newest bright young man.
刚从剑桥毕业不久，已经是国会成员了
Scarcely out of Cambridge and already a member of Parliament.
- 我就知道你会有作为的 - 谢谢
- I always felt you'd do well. - Thank you.
- 福克斯先生 - 好的，伊丽莎白夫人
- Mr. Fox. - Yes, Lady Elizabeth.
- 喜欢刚才的戏嘛？ - 坦白的说，不是很喜欢
- Did you enjoy the play? - I must confess, I did not entirely.
希望涉足政界的你…
I hope that you've not lost your sense of humor
- 那份幽默感还没丢 - 据我所知还在
- since entering politics. - Not that I'm aware.
那我想你应该知道
Then I'm sure you realize that School for Scandal
- “造谣学校”这部戏是一部喜剧 - 我知道
- was written as a comedy. - Yes.
但就我观戏的感受，这好像是一出悲剧
Although, from where I sat, it read as a tragedy.
公爵夫人！我们太想念您了
Your Grace! How we have missed you.
您不在的时候
In your absence,
伦敦成了最最无聊的城市
London has been reduced to the dreariest province.
这位就是剧作家谢里顿先生
And this, of course, is the playwright Mr. Sheridan.
请允许我介绍伊丽莎白・福斯特夫人
May I present the Lady Elizabeth Foster?
恕我无礼
I do not mean to be rude,
剧组全体正翘首企盼公爵夫人的接见呢
but I've an entire cast dying to meet the Duchess.
去去就回，我保证
I shall return you in a moment. Promise.
- 福克斯先生？ - 嗯
- Mr. Fox? - Yes.
借一句说话
A word.
让我上哪儿再去搜集这么多家庭琐事呢？
Well, wherever do I glean such domestic gossip?
- 这样做对公爵不太好吧？ - 我本来写的比这更夸张
- Were we fair on the Duke? - It could have been worse.
原先的剧本标题是“糟糕的婚姻”
My original title was The Bad Marriage.
他们一直都是这样的吗？
Is it always like this?
呃，正如他们所说
Well, as they say,
英格兰惟一不爱公爵夫人的男人
the Duke of Devonshire must be the only man in England
就是德文郡公爵本人
not in love with his wife.
- 夫人，这位是德文郡公爵夫人 - 很高兴认识您
- Her Grace, the Duchess of Devonshire. - Very pleased to meet you.
刚才你有没有忘却旧愁，尽情享受？
Were you at all able to forget things and enjoy yourself?
我玩得非常开心，谢谢你
It was a wonderful distraction, thank you.
那就好
Good.
- 整晚我都在和格雷先生说话 - 是么？
- I talked to Mr. Grey all evening. - Yes?
他正恋着你呢
He's in love with you.
亲爱的贝丝，我觉得他没有 恐怕情况恰好相反
My dear Bess, no, he is not. Quite the reverse, I fear.
他看你的那种方式，难道你看不出？
Well, can't you tell by the way he looks at you?
- 说真的，你真觉察不到么？ - 别说了
- Honestly, can't you tell? - Stop it.
乔治安娜，交媾并非只是为了生儿育女
Georgiana, intercourse is not just about offspring.
- 实际上，这是一件很有乐趣的事 - 是的，我懂
- In fact, it can be rather pleasurable. - Yes, I know.
闭上眼睛，试着设想
Close your eyes and try to envisage Grey
格雷正在解开你的衣裙，亲吻你的后背
opening your dress, kissing your back.
- 他们才不会这样做呢 - 不，他们会这么做
- They never do such things. - Yes, they do.
把眼睛闭上
Close your eyes.
格雷在你身后，慢慢褪去你的衣衫
Grey is behind you slowly opening your dress.
- 别这样，贝丝，快住手！ - 把眼睛闭上
- No, Bess, stop! - Close your eyes.
亲吻着你的背
Kissing your back.
就是这样
There.
明白了么？
See?
- 对不起，我离开一会儿 - 请原谅，先生们
- Would you excuse me for a minute? - You must excuse me, gentlemen.
- 夫人 - 格雷先生
- Your Grace. - Mr. Grey.
还有六周就要全国大选了，对不对？
The national election is in six weeks, yes?
竞选活动进展如何？
How is the campaign going?
很糟糕
Terribly.
我们只希望福克斯能在西敏斯特留任
Our only hope is to save Westminster for Fox.
你应该也知道，我这人常犯错
I have many faults, as you well know.
但至少在吸引注意力方面，我很在行
Not least among them is my ability to draw attention.
也许可以利用这一点为我方谋得利益
Perhaps we could use that to our advantage.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们，我要介绍一位先生
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you the man
他将告诉我们，什么才是应该做的
who will inform us of the work we must do
哪个党才值得我们信任 有请查尔斯・格雷先生
and of the party we so believe in. Mr. Charles Grey.
西敏斯特的好公民们！
Good people of Westminster!
这世界已走到灾难和浩劫的边缘！
The world is on the brink of disaster or salvation!
从法兰西到美利坚
From France to America,
从男人到女人，都在为自身自由而奋斗
men and women are struggling to free themselves,
他们在寻找生存的真义！
to find meaning in their existence!
变革就在我们眼前！
Change is upon us!
不能再走回老路了
We shall not go back to the old ways.
让我们带领英格兰勇敢迈进新世界
We shall take England into this brave new world
用一声惊雷震响整个天空！
and shake the thunder from the skies!
- 我表现如何？ - 说不上令人难堪
- How did I do? - I think it was not an embarrassment.
应该说非常精彩
It was a marvel.
我当时很紧张，您的大驾光临 使到场人数至少翻了三倍
I was nervous. Your presence trebled the numbers at least.
现在的我比刚才更加紧张
I'm nervous even now.
如果能赢下这场选举，执掌政权
If we win this election, if we get the power,
想想到时候我们会怎么做
think what we will do.
我们分开的时候，你会想我么？
Do you think of me when we're not together?
你该明白，那是肯定的
You ought to know I do.
- 在回答之前，你犹豫了 - 没有
- You hesitated before you replied. - No.
我不太习惯面对如此直接的提问
I'm unused to being asked so directly.
这么多人里，偏偏是你来问我
And by you, of all people.
我无时无刻不在想你，从未改变过
I think of you all the time. I always have.
- 夫人，您的马车在等您 - 谢谢
- Your carriage awaits, Your Grace. - Thank you.
…我们发誓！
...this we vow!
你们在伊丽莎白夫人的卧室外做什么？
What are you doing outside Lady Elizabeth's room?
她和谁在里面？
Who's in there with her?
英格兰有那么多女人 你偏要把她压在身子下面
Of all the women in England you had to throw yourself on her.
你的风流韵事，我从没表示过反对
I have never once objected to any of your affairs.
你安排的所有活动，我一概接受服从
I have accepted whatever arrangement you have proposed.
我还把夏洛特当作亲生女儿抚养
I have raised Charlotte as my own daughter.
但是这个…
But this...
好不容易才有一件属于自己的东西
I have one single thing of my own.
为什么不能把伊丽莎白留给我呢？
Why couldn't you let me keep Elizabeth for myself?
你究竟算什么玩意儿啊？
What kind of man are you?
她是我婚姻生活中仅有的慰藉 你却把我唯一的朋友生生抢走！
She is my sole comfort in our marriage. You have robbed me of my only friend!
我有什么不对？
What is wrong with me?
我…
I...
我从不认为自己是个善解人意的男人
I've never claimed to be a man of fine sensibility, G.
但我一直清楚这桩婚姻应该给我什么
But I've always known what I expect from this marriage
以及对此我该付出些什么
and what I'm prepared to give.
作为丈夫，我履行了应尽的义务
As a husband, I have fulfilled my obligations.
但是作为妻子
But, as a wife,
你却没有尽职尽责
you have not.
她必须离开，马上走
She has to go. Now.
不许她再踏进这个家一步！
She is never to set foot in this house again!
请注意控制你的情绪，乔 你似乎忘记了自己的身份
Do mind your temper, G. You're forgetting yourself.
我要她滚
I want her out.
我再也不想见到她 你下去跟她说，让她马上走
I never want to lay eyes on her again. Go down and tell her to leave at once.
我不会让她走的
I couldn't ask her that.
我不愿意这么做，乔
I won't do it, G.
- 第一眼见到她，我就不喜欢 - 你已经说过了，妈妈
- I never liked her from the first. - You made that quite clear, Mama.
她已经不在公爵宅邸了吧
She's gone from Devonshire House, I hope.
他们现在住在一起？
They're living there together?
乔治安娜！你怎么能答应这种事情？
Georgiana! What have you permitted to happen?
我不知道，我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
帮帮我，求你帮帮我，妈妈 告诉我应该怎么办
Help me. Help me, please, Mama. Tell me what to do.
给你的丈夫写信，坚持让他把人送走
You must write to your husband and insist he send her back
不管她原来住得多烂，哪儿来就回哪儿去
to whatever horrid little place she came from.
他不会照办的 他说过：“你想都别想”
He will not. "It is out of the question," he says.
那你就回去，继续履行你的义务
Then you must return and resume your duties.
让他明白，谁才是他的真爱
Make him realize whom he loves.
把政治活动和赌博游戏先放一放
You will give up your politics and your gambling.
你且专心做一回钟情的妻子
For once, you will devote yourself as a loving wife
安心完成当前的要务，给他生个儿子
and settle down to the task in hand, providing him with an heir.
很快他就会厌倦那个女人
Then he will soon tire of her.
你别无选择
You have no other option.
你好，乔
Hello, G.
威廉
William.
我虽无权把你赶出大宅
I may not have the authority to remove you from my house,
但我至少可以命令你滚出我的房间
but I can, at least, order you out of my room.
能不能容我解释？
Won't you please let me explain?
没什么好解释的
There is nothing to explain.
为了重新见到孩子，这是我唯一的机会
This is my only chance of ever seeing my children again.
公爵他是英格兰最有权势的贵族
The Duke is the most powerful peer in England.
我只有他这一根救命稻草
He is my only chance.
为夺回孩子而做的牺牲也得有个限度
There are limits to the sacrifices one makes for one's children.
不对，根本不可能有限度
No, there aren't. No limits whatsoever.
出去
Get out.
我们两个已经没什么可说的了
We have nothing more to say to one another.
妈妈，妈妈！
Mama, Mama!
能见到您太好了，妈妈
It's so nice to see you, Mama.
没错，这是一把猎枪
Right, this is a shotgun.
你妈妈说你对枪很感兴趣，是不是？
Your mother said you'd be interested, yes?
是的
Yes.
这是打火石，看见没有？
This is a flint. Do you see?
打火石击中这儿之后，就会产生火花
When the flint hits there, it causes a spark to happen.
然后火花会点燃火药，把子弹推出枪膛
Now, the spark, it lights the gunpowder and sends the bullet out of the gun.
- 你知道怎么拿枪么？ - 不知道，先生
- Do you know how to hold it? - No, sir.
是这么个拿法，把这东西顶在右肩上
Well, it's like that. Tuck it in there, into your right shoulder.
拿稳之后，把那只手往前挪一点
Hold it firmly, then you can move that hand a little further along.
感觉到它有多重了吗？身体得稍稍前倾
Can you feel how heavy it is? You have to lean into it a bit.
睁大双眼，顺着枪管看前方
And keep both eyes open. Look right along the barrel.
就像这样，看着前面
Right along there just like that.
砰！来，我示范给你看
Bang! Here, let me show you.
瞧那儿
There.
枪很沉，对不对？
It's quite heavy, isn't it?
你口干么？要不要喝点东西？
Are you thirsty? Would you like something to drink?
各位先生口渴么？要不要喝点什么？
Are you gentlemen thirsty? Would you like something to drink?
谢谢你
Thank you.
公爵知道你要和谁见面吗？
Did you tell the Duke who you were meeting?
不知道
No.
- 他没问过？ - 没有
- Did he even ask? - No.
他的脑子在想别的事
He has other things on his mind.
你也一样
As do you.
向我倾诉心事，能不能让你好受一些？
Would it help to unburden yourself?
我没什么能向你倾诉的
It's nothing I can discuss with you.
而且，说这些只会令人厌烦
Besides, it would only bore.
你没必要总想着让别人好受
You don't have to please others all the time.
从小到大，我一直在学如何让别人好受 要忘却这些东西，很难
It's what I've been brought up to do. Difficult lesson to unlearn.
允许我发表几句评论么？
Would you permit me an observation?
我觉得你这么做，是为了让别人喜欢你
I believe you do it so that people will love you.
- 这么说有什么根据呢？ - 根据本人的所见所闻
- What makes you say that? - From what I've seen.
你的丈夫，你的朋友，特别是贝丝夫人…
With your husband, your friends, especially Lady Bess,
连大众也是一样
even the public.
我以前从没这么想过
I never thought of it that way before.
你让我觉得自己更加可悲了
You make me sound so pitiable.
乔治安娜
Georgiana.
我不该无礼多嘴，向你道歉
I've gone beyond my brief. I apologize.
请相信我，说这些都是为了你好
Please believe it was only for your sake that I spoke.
求求你告诉我，究竟是哪儿不对
Please, tell me what is wrong.
我怕有些事自己做得太迟
I fear I've done some things in life too late
而有些事来得又太早
and others too early.
不，你没有
No, you haven't.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧
All right.
什么“好吧”？
"All right"?
你们俩彼此相爱么？
Do you love each other?
- 乔治安娜… - 大人，您爱贝丝吗？
- Georgiana... - Do you love Bess, Your Grace?
- 你究竟想说什么？ - 我对他没有要求
- Where is all this leading? - I make no demands on him.
- 那你呢贝丝，你爱我丈夫吗？ - 爱他就和爱你一样多
- And, Bess, do you love my husband? - As I do you.
这么说你想留在这里？
And so you intend to stay?
威廉要我留在这里
William has asked that I do.
你的内心就没想过要拒绝他？
You couldn't find it in your heart to refuse him?
没有
No.
那我们做一笔交易吧
Then let us make a deal.
- 一笔交易？ - 是的
- A deal? - Yes.
我愿意成全你们两个
I give you my blessing
只要你肯接受我对查尔斯・格雷的感情
if you will accept my feelings for Charles Grey.
一开始我没意识到
I didn't realize it at first.
我以为那也许只是逢场作戏
I thought that perhaps it was only a dalliance.
和他在一起能让我快乐
It can make me happy.
一笔交易？一笔交易
A deal? A deal.
我从不做什么交易
I don't make deals.
有这必要么？
Why would I?
我掌控着一切
I'm in charge of it all.
我可以把他约出来，然后责问他
You know, I would call him out. I would challenge him.
- 我会用子弹射穿他的脑袋 - 威廉
- I'd put a bullet in his head. - William.
别说话 你铁了心，想让我变成别人的笑柄？
Be quiet. Are you determined to make me a total laughingstock?
给一个无法续嗣的男人再戴一顶绿帽子？
A man who cannot sire a son, and then a cuckold?
威廉，乔治安娜只想问问我们…
William. Georgiana only asks what we ourselves...
不许说话，婊子！
Be quiet, woman!
- 你跟他苟且了？ - 没有
- Are you his whore? - No.
我也不明白，你为什么如此介意
But I can't see why you'd mind.
- 你已经有贝丝和三个儿子了！ - 三个儿子？
- You have Bess and three boys! - Three boys?
你说我会认那些个小杂种做继承人嘛？
Do you think I can make those bastards my heirs?
嗯？你说说看？
Well? Do you?
威廉！
William!
你压根就不了解我，是不是？
You don't know me in the least, do you?
不，我了解你，我们完全不合拍
Yes, I do. We're a bad match.
结婚时我对你只有两个要求：忠贞和后嗣
I asked but two things when we wed, loyalty and a male heir.
和你对狗的要求有什么两样！
The same as your dogs!
不，不许碰我！别碰我！
No, don't touch me! Don't touch me!
走开！
Get off!
放开我！
Get off me!
你就是这样对她的？ 你就是这样对待那个娼妇的？
Is this how you treat her? Is this how you treat your whore?
不！不！
No! No!
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
不！
No!
来，夏洛特，跟我走
Come with me. Charlotte, come with me.
不！不！
No! No!
给我生个儿子，在此之前 呆在这里，按我说的去做
Give me a son. Until then, stay here and do as I say.
下面有请本次的赢家―福克斯先生 民众的宠儿！
I give you the winner. Mr. Fox, the man of the people!
我要请出的是我们的秘密武器 德文郡公爵夫人
And I give you the weapon, the Duchess of Devonshire.
谢谢
Thank you.
在场的所有人，谢谢你们 今天能来参加我的欢迎会
Thank you, all of you, for this reception today.
我们今天赢了选举，明天我们将勾画未来！
Today we have won the vote. Tomorrow we define the future!
- 大人 - 大人
- Your Grace. - Your Grace.
夫人
Your Grace.
- 夫人 - 夫人
- Your Grace. - Your Grace.
夫人能赏光与在下跳一支舞么？
Will Your Grace give me the favor of a dance?
小心，乔
Steady, G.
- 着火了！ - 乔治安娜！
- Fire! - Georgiana!
夫人！
Your Grace!
夫人的头发！
Her Grace's hair!
别愣着！
Do something!
请把夫人发套上的火给灭了
Please put out Her Grace's hair.
夫人需要休息
Her Grace needs to rest.
如果严遵医嘱
As long as she follows strict instructions
夫人生产时应该不会有什么大碍
there should be no impediment to the birth.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
公爵夫人有孕在身
The Duchess is pregnant.
还有这个
And there.
谢谢你，希顿
Thank you, Heaton.
进来
Come.
夫人
Your Grace.
根据夫人的有关继承条款，这个给您
As per the terms of His Grace's inheritance, this is for you
您可自由支配
to spend as you wish.
终于成功了
Success at last.
乔治安娜
Georgiana.
其实这件事情，我也很厌恶
I, too, abhor this whole thing.
再要一张，还是不要了？
Twist or stick?
- 不要了 - 不要了？
- Stick. - Stick?
那我也不要了
I'll stick, too, then.
现在亮牌
Let's see.
你赢了，干得漂亮
You won. Well done.
驾
Come on.
妈妈，你忘记摸牌了
Mama, you forgot to deal.
- 夫人 - 格雷先生
- Your Grace. - Mr. Grey.
- 你从法兰西被召回了？ - 是暂时的
- You are recalled from France? - For a while.
革命还没开始？
No revolution yet?
还没开始，但这只是时间问题
No, not yet, but it's only a matter of time.
- 你怎么会来这里？ - 我收到了一封请柬
- How is it you are here? - I received an invitation.
我想大概是党内的事，不好拒绝
I assumed it was on behalf of the Party. I could not say no.
那是当然
Of course.
我生了一个儿子
I bore a son.
是嘛
Yes.
他名叫威廉・乔治・斯宾塞・卡文迪什
His name is William George Spencer Cavendish,
哈廷顿侯爵，我们都叫他哈特
Marquis of Hartington. We call him Hart.
你和公爵一定很高兴吧
You and the Duke must be very pleased.
是的
We are.
公爵去伦敦举行欢庆仪式了
The Duke has gone to London to celebrate.
很想念你
You have been missed.
非常非常想念
Much missed.
- 十个筹码押皇后 - 四个筹码押五点
- Ten on the Queen. - Four on five.
下注时间结束
And no more bets, please.
四点输了
The losing card, four.
皇后赢了
The winning card, Queen.
很好，八个筹码押三点
Jolly good. Eight on the three.
押五个筹码在五点上
Put five on the five.
押五点的还没赢过呢，乔
All of the fives have gone, G.
我太累了，不想玩了
I think I'm too tired to play.
- 先生们，告退 - 夫人慢走
- Gentlemen. - Your Grace.
乔治安娜
Georgiana.
别让任何人知道
No one must know.
- 格雷是你请来的啊 - 晚安
- You summoned Grey. - Good night.
我打算去一趟巴斯
I was thinking about going to Bath.
贝丝，这次我去疗养 你就待在这儿，陪着我们的丈夫吧
Bess, you can stay here and look after our husband whilst I take the cure.
好啊…你说呢，威廉？
Yes, William. Why not?
让乔先去，等你有空了 我们再去那儿和她会合
If G goes now, we can catch up with her when you're free.
既然你坚持，那就这样吧
Well, if you must.
(巴斯新闻报)
“昨天，德文郡公爵夫人 戴着花边高帽来到了巴斯”
"The Duchess of Devonshire appeared last week in Bath in a mobcap.
“夫人自从投身竞选事业之后…”
"Her Grace, ever since initiation into the business of electioneering,
“似乎更钟情花边高帽了”
"has been much attached to the mobs."
很好嘛
Very good.
你最喜欢哪一个？
So which one is your favorite?
- 看这张 - 嗯
- This one. - Yeah.
这张图里的你似乎手气不错 终于连胜了几把
In this one it seems you've hit a winning streak, for once.
不错啊
Very good.
这张图里的你…
And in this one you see...
穿这样的裙子很适合吸引投票者啊
Is that dress really an appropriate way to attract voters?
你们这帮政客，根本不懂什么是时尚
You politicians know absolutely nothing about fashion.
如果你真想问我最喜欢哪一个
But if you were to really ask me which my favorite was,
那就是我面前的这一个
I'd say it was this one.
- 早上好，查尔斯 - 早上好
- Morning, Charles. - Morning.
祝您愉快，先生
Good day to you, sir.
很完美，谢谢你
It's perfect. Thank you.
我们想给你一个惊喜，乔
Thought we would surprise you, G.
我记得你曾经说过 在你我的婚姻中自发的东西太少
I think you once said there wasn't enough spontaneity in our marriage
或者类似意思的话
or words to that effect.
妈妈，你来这里干嘛？
Mama, what are you doing here?
你在巴斯，应该见了不少朋友吧
So, have you seen many of our circle in Bath?
见了一些
Some.
寇克斯家族，哈沃福德，维克罗勋爵
The Cokes and Haverford and Lord Wicklow.
也见了不少政客吧？开会之类的
Bunch of politicos, too, aren't there? Meetings and such.
我想是吧
I believe.
格雷他来了没有？ 我说的是查尔斯・格雷先生
Is Grey here? By which I mean Mr. Charles Grey.
听说他也在这儿
Rumor has it that he is.
- 我不会放弃他的 - 乔治安娜
- I won't give him up. - Georgiana.
人人都有情人，贝丝就是我丈夫的情人
Everyone has a lover. Bess is the lover of my husband.
如果你还有判断力的话
If you had shown some discretion,
- 事情就不至于此 - 不至于此？
- it might have been different. - Different?
不幸中的万幸是，这事还没被捅到报纸上
The only good fortune is it hasn't yet made it to the papers.
亲爱的，格雷他还是单身，没钱没地位
My dear, Grey is unmarried. He has no wealth, no rank.
这桩丑闻于他丝毫无损 所有的危险都在你这边
He risks nothing with this affair. The hazard is all yours.
- 格雷他爱我 - 威廉也爱你
- Grey loves me. - So does William.
没错，我爱你
Yes. I love you.
怎么个爱法？
How?
用我所理解的方式来表达爱
In the way I understand love.
乔治安娜，你闹得太过火了 此事有损我们的尊严
Georgiana, this has gone much too far. It is beneath our dignity.
- 伦敦上下都在谈论 - 让他们说去吧
- All London is talking. - Let them talk.
如果是格雷让我变得堕落，那正好
If Grey makes me a fallen woman, well and good.
威廉就能和我离婚 让贝丝做德文郡公爵夫人
Now William may divorce me and Bess becomes Duchess of Devonshire.
这事决不可能发生
That will never happen.
这事还是由你自己去解决吧
I think I will leave you to it.
接下来呢？
What follows now?
你是不是会扯掉我的衣服 再在我的身上施一次淫威？
Are you going to tear my clothes off and force yourself upon me again?
我为什么要那么做？
Why on earth would I do that?
对我的举止和才智，你从来没尊重过
I know that you've never thought much of my manners or my intellect, G.
但事实上，我从不做毫无意义的事情
But, in fact, I never do anything that serves no purpose.
我非常清楚你们两个发生了什么
I know precisely what you two have together.
- 我们彼此相爱 - 对此我毫不怀疑
- We love each other. - I do not doubt it.
他和你一样，是个理想主义者
He is a dreamer like yourself,
你们俩都在幻想另一个虚幻的世界 那世界非但不存在，以后也不会有
and you both dream of another world that does not exist and it never will.
现实是什么样，还是让我来开导你吧
As for reality, allow me to enlighten you.
如果你不肯立即放弃这个男人
If you do not give him up at once, I will see to it
我定会让他在这个国家无家可归，一文不名
that every home and every checkbook in this country is closed to him.
无论是国会厅前还是相府帏后
He will be welcomed neither in the halls of government
他都会被扫地出门
nor in its backrooms of power.
他立志成为首相的梦想
His dream of becoming prime minister
还有你们改变世界的共同心愿 全都会灰飞烟灭
and your mutual fantasy of a changed world will be dead as ash.
你也别想再见到你的孩子了
And you will never see your children again.
乔治安娜
Georgiana.
我请您即回伦敦
I must ask you to return to London.
- 你不走？ - 嗯
- Without you? - Yes.
这些是我们女儿写的
These are from our girls.
小哈特还不会写字 当然了，他还不满一岁
Little Hart neglected to write, but then, of course, he's not yet one.
- 这将是你一生最大的错误 - 错了
- This will be the mistake of your life. - No.
许多年之前，我就已经犯过了
I made that many years ago.
我相信你自己能出去
I trust you can see yourself out.
- 该死的，快把门打开！ - 大人
- Damn you, man, open the door! - Your Grace.
妈妈，妈妈，妈妈，妈妈！
Mama, Mama, Mama, Mama!
妈妈，妈妈，妈妈
Mama, Mama, Mama.
- 走吧，姑娘们 - 我爱你，妈妈
- Come on, girls. - Mama. I love you.
快点，姑娘们，妈妈很快就会出来的
Girls, run along. Your mother will join you in a minute.
快点
Come on.
走吧
Run along.
乔
G.
你我终于达成了协议
You must know how greatly pleased I am
你知道我有多高兴么
that we have come to an arrangement.
小孩子离开母亲太久了，对她们可不好
It's not good for little ones to be without their mother for so long.
- 为了这，就要赔上我的一生 - 有个解决的办法
- My life for theirs. - That's one way of putting it.
你妈妈把这叫做 “个人满足之前的习惯礼数”
Your mother called it "common decency before personal gratification,"
或者类似的话，具体形容我记不清了
or some such thing. The exact words escape me.
是不是“监禁在自己的家中”？
How about "imprisoned in my own house"?
不是，她不是这么说的
No. That's not how she put it.
如果是这种说法，我会记得的
I would have remembered that.
乔治安娜！
Georgiana!
放开我！
Unhand me!
乔治安娜！
Georgiana!
乔治安娜！你能不能放手？
Georgiana! Will you please unhand me?
请原谅
Excuse me.
乔治安娜！求求你
Georgiana! Please.
乔治安娜！
Georgiana!
- 谢谢，伯利 - 放开他
- Thank you, Burleigh. - Let him go.
我每天写十几封信，可你一封都没回
I have written a dozen times a day. Still, there is nothing from you.
出什么事了？难道你不再爱我了？
What has happened? Do you love me no longer?
- 我对你的感觉没有改变 - 那我们就应该在一起
- My personal feelings remain unaltered. - Then we must be together again.
我要娶你，要你为我生儿育女
I want to marry you. I want you to bear my children.
生的是男还是女，我不在乎！
And I don't care if they're boys or girls!
- 要能像你说的就好了 - 当然能，一定会的
- I wish it could be that way. - It can. It will.
这一路总会有艰难苦痛
Sorrows will come however we try to avoid them.
我们必须坚持到底，决不让步
We must stay the course and never give in.
- 不，查尔斯 - 离开这儿，跟我走
- No, Charles. - You must leave and be with me.
做个自由的女人，走吧！我们现在就走！
A free woman. Now! Let us leave now!
我不能丢下我的孩子
I cannot abandon my children.
自己好好想想，你刚才叫我做的事
Listen to what you are asking me to do.
怎么了？这鸽子不对你的口味？
What's the matter? Don't like the pigeon?
我觉得还满好吃的
I find it quite decent.
我肚里怀着查尔斯・格雷的孩子
I'm carrying Charles Grey's child.
请把我的决定告诉公爵夫人
Please be so kind as to inform the Duchess of my decision.
事情安排如下
This is how it will be.
你会被带到乡下，在那儿生下孩子
You will be taken to the country where you will give birth to the child,
孩子将交给查尔斯・格雷的家人 由其抚养
and the child will be trusted to the care of Charles Grey's family.
你听见了吗？
Are you listening?
她应该都听到了，我们走吧
I think she's heard you. Let's leave her.
- 乔治安娜，回答我 - 我说了，我们走
- Georgiana, please. - I said let's leave.
这不是商量，我的决定她已经知道了
This is not a discussion. She's been informed of my decision.
- 给她一点同情吧，威廉 - 要什么同情啊
- Have pity on her, William. - Pity be damned.
你也清楚，这是她自找的
She's brought this upon herself, as well you know.
- 走吧 - 不，我和她一起去
- Now come. - No. I will go with her.
你哪儿也不准去
But you're not going anywhere.
如果乔要我去，我就跟她走
I will go with G, if G will have me,
你说什么做什么都没用，阻拦不了我们
and there's nothing you can do or say to stop either of us.
- 谢谢你来陪我 - 我一定得陪在你身边
- Thank you for coming. - I couldn't not be with you.
该动身了
It's time.
- 要不要… - 不用，我来抱她
- Would it help... - No, I must take her.
夫人，我是格雷将军
Your Grace, I'm General Grey.
查尔斯在哪儿？
Where's Charles?
你丈夫觉得这事最好由我出面
Your husband thought it best if I took care of this.
格雷将军
General Grey.
她的名字是伊莱莎
Her name is Eliza.
好了
Come on.
好了，乔，抱着我，抱着我
Come on, G. I've got you. I've got you.
在个人性情方面
I'm not particularly adept at expressing myself
我不太擅于表达自己
when it comes to matters of a more personal nature.
但我会努力的
But I shall try.
这些年以来，我的行为方式
Over the years, I have acted in ways
可能让你觉得太过严苛
that you have judged to be harsh.
我不想让你遭受更多痛苦了
Well, I do not wish for you to undergo any further suffering.
事实上，我希望我们两个能和平相处
In fact, I would like our lives to find a calm normality.
为了祝贺你长假归来
Lady Melbourne has arranged a small gathering
梅尔本夫人安排了一场小型聚会
in honor of your recent return from holiday.
过去这一年，外面流传着不少风言风语
And given some of the vague reports that have been circulating this past year
我想我们双双出席就是最好的还击
I think it would be wise for us to go.
向世人证明，我们已经和好如初
A show of unity, so to speak.
有哪些人出席？
Who will be there?
所有人
Everybody.
那好吧
As you wish.
那样无拘无束，多好啊
How wonderful to be that free.
过来啊
Come here.
过来，小乔，过来
Come here. Little G, come here.
德文郡公爵和公爵夫人 伊丽莎白・福斯特夫人
The Duke and Duchess of Devonshire and Lady Elizabeth Foster.
- 夫人 - 见到你太好了
- Your Grace. - It's lovely to see you.
欢迎回来，夫人
Welcome back, Your Grace.
请原谅
Excuse me.
- 欢迎回来 - 欢迎回家，夫人
- Welcome back. - Welcome home, Your Grace.
- 欢迎回来 - 欢迎回来，乔
- Welcome back. - Welcome back, G.
大家都很想念你
Your presence has been sorely missed.
对不起，离开一会儿
Would you excuse me?
- 格雷先生 - 夫人
- Mr. Grey. - Your Grace.
相信您的旅程一定很愉快
I trust your tour was enjoyable.
是的
Yes.
我们在瑞士度夏，又去了尼斯避冬
We spent the summer in Switzerland and the winter in Nice.
在这里我代表大家
Well, I speak on behalf of everybody
为您能平安返回而感到由衷高兴
when I say how glad I am that you have arrived home safely.
你最近怎么样？
And what news with you?
我马上就要订婚了
I'm to be engaged.
和庞森比小姐
To Lady Ponsonby.
很快就会通知大家
The announcement will follow shortly.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我有个侄女，伊莱莎
And I have a niece, Eliza,
我非常疼爱她
who is very much loved.
哪天你来见见她吧
One day you should come and meet her,
如果你愿意
in a little while.
可以过一阵子就来
If you would like.
我非常愿意
I would like that very much.
乔治安娜重归上流社会 成为同时代最具盛名与权势的女性
查尔斯・格雷后来当选为首相
乔治安娜、贝丝和公爵共同生活在一起 直到乔治安娜离世
带着乔治安娜临终前的祝福 贝丝嫁入爵门，成为新的德文郡公爵夫人
看你们谁能抓到我？
Who's going to catch me first?
- 我！ - 快点，姑娘们
- Me! - Quick, girls.
快来啊，否则我就跑掉喽！
Quick, I'm going to get away!
快啊，姑娘们，别停下
Come on, girls, keep running.
乔治安娜常与伊莱莎秘密见面
伊莱莎将自己的女儿取名为“乔治安娜”
我爱你，我也爱你
And I love you, and I love you.